# Lisa Boylan

SOFTWARE/RDBMS DEVELOPMENT | ENTERPRISE IMPLEMENTATIONS | SYSTEMS ARCHITECTURE/ENGINEERING | PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Email: lboylan7@yahoo.com

Over 25 years of combined progressive experience in management and the software technology industry. Leveraging technology experience and encouraging entrepreneurial spirit and passion, to enable teams to build and deliver pioneering solutions to challenging problems.

## **Career Highlights**

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# MANAGEMENT | SOFTWARE/RDBMS DEVELOPMENT | ENTERPRISE IMPLEMENTATIONS | SYSTEMS ARCHITECTURE/ENGINEERING

- -- Project Manager with a proven record of success leading all phases of diverse technology projects; payroll, healthcare, financial, retail, database, and custom software. Business management experience meeting timeline and budgetary targets.
- -- Business Strategist; plan and manage business projects aligning business goals with technology solutions. Drive process improvements, competitive advantage and bottom-line gains.
- -- Effective communicator; leverage technical, business and financial acumen to communicate effectively with clients, executives and respective teams. Known for extreme flexibility and collaboration to produce high-quality results.
- -- Developer, Designer, Architect; experienced in Agile, Extreme, SCRUM, RUP and Waterfall. Enjoy coding with experience in C, C++, OO Modeling, Phython, Java, and shell scripting.
- -- System Administrator; Linux, Microsoft

#### **Lead Software Engineer/Owner**

Danville and Alamo Pet Stores 01/2005-03/2017

- -- Initiated Internet retail marketing analysis. Conceived and proto-typed creative low cost solution. Demonstration to local non-profit received enthusiastic support for the solutions ability to increase membership and multiple revenue streams.
- -- Utilized strategic analysis and planning to implement new services generating additional \$27,000 in net income and yearly growth in service revenues of 25%.
- -- Successfully implemented and trained 25 employees in best practice processes, standards and customer relationship building skills as evidenced by business growth from 1 to 2 stores.
- -- Identified and established mutually beneficial key relationships with local vendors, non-profits, police, and schools. Relationships reduced marketing costs from \$18000 to \$3000, and increased sales by 5%.
- -- Designed and implemented software solutions, combined with vendor negotiations, reduced COGS 10%.

#### **Data Architect (Consultant)**

Kaiser Permanente 04/2004-02/2005

Analyzed multiple web applications to produce data management functional requirements and architecture. Quantified 800 TB storage equirement, recommended and initiated creation of Data Dictionary and Model. Created project plan which included 14 design phases and resource requirements. Through cross-functional collaboration, identified existing corporate data warehouse project reducing time, costs and streamlined resources.

### Senior Java Software Engineer/ Project Manager

ADP (formerly ProBusiness) 07/1999-03/1999

Managed and monitored scope, cost, and scheduled projects. Applied SDLC techniques to build tighter structure for planning, reporting, tracking, coding, change control and issue/risk management.

Achievements:

- -- Mentored team of five, designing wireless Procurement Object Model (POM). Drove analysis of five industry standards, open source and market solutions. Through team consensus, established requirements, designed over 2500 attributes and 200 classes.
- -- Presented POM to C-suite executives and international Angel investors resulting in patent submission and startup venture.
- -- Using OO design models, JAVA, HTML and JDBC, created reusable, extensible Java validation system incorporating XML for ease of customization, management and integrity across multiple platforms.
- -- Team member of International Payroll/ERP/CRM ASP system feasibility study. Collaborating with international unions and HR representatives, identified and documented functional regulatory employee privacy requirements. Presented functional requirements on time to C-suite executives.
- -- Directed WAP proof-of-concept for multi-million dollar business opportunity.

### Senior Java Software Engineer / Project Manager

InterPro 03/2003 - 09/2003

Analysis of persistence, localization, data storage, distributed application management resulted in technical and performance requirements and ASP prototype. Produced functional object models for major JAVA subsystems.

# Software Engineer/Database & Enterprise Management/System Administration

**Earlier Career** 

-- **Software Engineering**: Managed all phases of SDLC, completing assignments to enhance automated data/voice/process applications within UNIX, network and client/server environments. Solutions were robust, scalable and secure. CLIENTS: Levi Strauss, Schwab. Zacson and Airtouch, UNOCAL, Informix. LANGUAGES: C, JAVA, Python, HTML, CSS, proprietary, and scripting languages.

RESULTS: Completed projects on time, on budget and to universal client satisfaction.

- -- Database Management: Guided teams in the development and architecture of relational database management systems (RDBMS). CLIENTS: Kraft, Levis Strauss, AutobyTel. Kaiser, Zacson. RESULTS: Improved the efficiency, recovery and scalability of applications and data
- -- **Enterprise Management:** Integrated, ported, architected and improved functioning of databases, network systems, software, server configurations and security. CLIENTS: LSI, Levi, Zacson, HP.
- -- **System Integrations/Migrations:** Project-managed large-scale initiatives involving transition and integration of applications to new platforms and merger of disparate systems. CLIENTS: LSI Logic, Levi, HP. RESULTS: Achieved seamless migrations and integrations with no unscheduled downtime.
- -- **System Administration:** Implemented firewalls, directed RDBMS installations, software installations, hardware and software upgrades, network management. CLIENTS: LSI, Levi, Sun Microsystems.

#### **Georgia Institute of Technology**

**EDUCATION** 

Master Computer Science (OMSCS), Computer Software Engineering

2017-2020

**University of California, Berkeley** 

**Bachelor Computer Science**